-=TLF字幕组=- 荣誉出品
翻译：诗 琪
君临
King's Landing
翻译：Hello_Agnes
翻译：LordVader
翻译：lydia萌
卡林湾
Moat Cailin
校对：LordVader
统筹：饭离烨
临冬城
WinterFell
特效：离太阳只有七步
绝境长城
The Wall
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据乔治·R·R·马丁著《冰与火之歌》改编
权力的游戏
第四季   第九集
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
电视剧编剧
戴维·贝尼奥夫 & D·B·威斯
导演
尼尔·马歇尔
长城上的守夜人
What was she like?
她長的什麼樣
She...
她…
she had red hair.
她長著紅頭髮
Oh?
哦？
- How big were her feet? - What do you want me to say?
- 她腳多大？
- 你到底想讓我說什麼？
I want you to tell me what it was like to have someone.
我想讓你跟我講講，擁有一個人是什麼滋味
To be with someone.
和一個人在一起
To love someone and have them love you back.
愛著一個人，被人愛著是什麼滋味
We're all gonna die a lot sooner than I'd planned.
我們的死期比我預想的要早得多
You're the closest I'll ever get to knowing.
你是我認識的人裏面最親近的一個
So you and Gilly never?
你跟吉莉沒有？
No.
沒有
She just had a baby.
她剛生孩子
And she never offered.
她從沒提出過
But if she had,
但如果她提出
you would have?
你會嗎？
You'd have broken your vows?
打破誓言？
The interesting thing is,
有趣的是
our vows never specifically forbid
誓言沒有禁止…
intimate relations with women.
跟女人保持親密的關係
What?
什麼？
"I shall take no wife,"
「我將不娶妻」
yes, that's in there. There's no denying that.
沒錯，這句話是在誓言裏頭，毫無疑問
"I shall father no children." It's very specific.
「不生子」，這個也很明確
But what do our vows have to say about other...
但是我們的誓言裏也沒提到不能做其他的活動
activities is open to interpretation.
那是有待商榷的
I don't think Ser Alliser cares much for interpretation.
我覺得艾裏沙爵士才不會管那麼多
Anyway, there's nothing for him to interpret.
無論如何，沒什麼好商榷的
We didn't.
我們沒幹啥
So what's it like?
到底是什麼感覺？
It's...
是…
there's this person, this whole other person.
有這樣一個人，一個完完整整的人
And you're wrapped up in them and they're wrapped up in you.
她裹著你，你裹著她
And you--
而你…
for a little--
有那麼…
for a little while, you're more than just you.
有那麼一會兒，你不再是一個人…
You're-- I don't know. I'm not a bleeding poet.
你就…我不知道，我又不是個該死的詩人
No, you're really not.
是啊，你確實不是
What did I get for it?
我又得到什麼了？
An arrow six inches from my heart.
一箭穿膛，離心臟就6英吋
There'll be arrows for all of us soon, I imagine.
我估計，我們很快都免不了中箭
There will.
是啊
They've already done the worst thing to me they could ever do.
他們對我已經壞事做盡了
Go get some sleep, Sam.
去睡覺吧，山姆
I'll take this watch.
這輪我放哨
Did I ever tell you about her?
我跟你說過她嗎？
- My Sheila? - Yes.
- 我的小姑娘？
- 說過
That was a night to remember.
記得那是在一個晚上
Of course, I'd had a good bit to drink.
我的確是喝了點兒酒
Her fangs were sharp,
她那尖牙真是鋒利
but she knew how to use them.
但是她也不會來
And she was nice and soft down below.
她下面那麼美好，柔軟
No, she was no ordinary beast.
她可真是非同尋常的野獸
Many is the man who--
曼尼是個…
I know you never fucked a bear.
我知道你沒幹過熊
You know you never fucked a bear.
你自己心裏也清楚
Right now I don't want to think about the bear you never fucked.
現在，我不要想你那只沒跟你搞過的熊
Right now all I want to think about
現在，我只要全心全意地思考
is each one of these arrows finding its way into a crow's heart.
怎麼把這些箭射進烏鴉的心臟
We could be waiting here a while.
我們得在這兒等上一陣子
Good.
很好
The longer we wait, the more arrows I'll have.
等的時間越長，我就能做越多的箭
They came up here to our land
他們來到我們的土地上
and put up a big wall and said it was theirs.
建了一堵大牆，就說這地方是他們的
Then they started hunting us down.
然後開始追殺我們
This time, we're the ones doing the hunting.
這一次，該我們追殺他們
You've got a lot to say about killing.
說到殺人，你可真是滔滔不絕
Even more words than arrows.
說出的字比做成的箭還多
Back in those villages, I killed just as many of them as you did.
在那些村子裏，我殺的人跟你一樣多
More, I reckon.
不，估計比你多
Yes, but none of those were your crow lover.
是啊，但沒一個是你的烏鴉情人
I probably killed him already.
我說不定已經把他給殺了
So you've said.
你這句話我可記住了
And if not,
要是他沒死
the only thing left of him is gonna be his fun bits hanging around my neck.
我就把他那話兒割下來掛在脖子上
More words.
話更多了
Know what I think you do when you see him?
知道我覺得你見到他會做什麼嗎？
Serve him up a nice juicy slice of ginger minge.
用你那精美多汁的逼去伺候他
You been thinking about that ginger minge?
你是不是一直惦記著逼？
Wondering what it tastes like?
想知道它是什麼味道嗎？
Maybe I have.
我可能嘗過哦
Jon Snow is mine.
瓊恩·雪諾是我的
Anyone else tries to kill him,
誰要是敢殺他
I'll have an arrow for them.
我就射他一箭
And not one of your bald friends is fast enough to stop me.
你們這些光頭誰也快不過我，別想阻止我
And what is it that couldn't wait until morning, Tarly?
塔利，什麼事情這麼重要不能等到明早再做？
Maester Aemon.
伊蒙學士
- How did you know-- - That it was you?
- 你怎麼知道是我？
- 是你？
Who else but Samwell Tarly
除了山姆威爾·塔利…
would be wasting candles
還有誰浪費蠟燭…
to read in the middle of the night?
在深夜裏讀書？
- Let me help you. - Oh, no need.
- 我來幫你
- 不用了
I know my way around this library
我很瞭解圖書館這一片
better than any other place in Castle Black.
比對黑城堡其他地方要瞭解的多
Thousands of books
這裏有成千上萬的書
and no eyes to read them.
卻沒人來讀
Old age is a wonderful source of ironies
老來閱遍無盡諷刺
if nothing else.
沒別的
But you didn't answer my question.
但是你還沒回答我的問題
What are you reading?
你在讀什麼？
Maester Faull.
缶爾學士
Ah, the wildlings.
哦，是那些野人
I can assure you that the closest Maester Faull
我很確信
ever got to a wildling was this very library.
缶爾學士距離野人最近的地方就是這個圖書館了
But what he says about what they do,
但是他說的有關野人做過的事情
it's all true.
都是真的
It's exactly what the survivors of their raids report.
存活下來的人都是這麼報告的
Yes, imagine the stories wildlings tell about us.
是啊，想想那些我們講過的野人故事
Love is the death of duty.
愛情，是職責的墳墓
I told that to your friend Jon Snow once.
我跟你的朋友瓊恩·雪諾說過一次
He didn't listen and neither did you.
他聽不進去，你也聽不進去
Which is why you've abandoned your watch atop the Wall
這就是為什麼你不在那長城上守著
to come here and read about the terrible things
卻到這兒來讀這些的…
that may have happened to the girl you love.
你愛的女孩的可怕遭遇
I don't love her.
我不愛她
- Yes, you do. - No.
- 不，你愛她
- 不是的
Yes, you do.
你愛她
Heard it in your voice when you first brought her to me.
你第一次帶她見我時，我就聽出來了
I remember how it sounds.
我還記得戀愛的語氣
I was in love once.
我也曾戀愛過
You were?
你戀愛過？
You can imagine all manner of horrors
你能想像出那女人和孩子
befalling that poor girl and her child.
可能會經歷的各種可怕遭遇
Is it so difficult to imagine
卻很難想像
that an old person was once,
一個老人曾經
more or less, like you?
也會像你這樣？
I'm sorry, Maester.
抱歉，學士
I didn't mean it like that.
我不是那個意思
Do you know who I was before I came here?
你知道我來這裏之前是什麼身份嗎？
What I could have been if I'd only said the word?
你知道當初只要我開口，就會獲得什麼地位嗎？
Of course you do.
你肯定知道
I met many girls when I was Aemon Targaryen.
當我還是伊蒙·坦格利安的時候，見識過很多女人
A future king always does.
儲君都是如此
Some of them were quite forward
一些女人很主動
in their attempts to win my affections.
想博得我的垂青
One of them succeeded.
其中一人成功了
I was very young.
我當時很年輕
Who was she?
她是誰？
Ah.
啊
I could tell you everything about her.
我可以告訴你她的一切
Who she was,
她是誰
how we met,
我們如何相遇
the color of her eyes,
她眼睛的顏色
and the shape of her nose.
鼻子的形狀
I can see her
我能看見她…
right in front of me.
就在我面前
She's more real than you are.
對我來說她比你還要真實
We could spend all night trading tales of lost loves.
我們可以整晚不睡，互相講述愛情故事
Nothing makes the past a sweeter place to visit
死亡臨近最容易讓人…
than the prospect of imminent death.
沉醉於懷舊
Go to bed, Tarly.
去睡覺吧，塔利
Sorry, I can't open the gate for anybody. Orders.
抱歉，我不能給任何人開門，這是命令
You don't understand. They killed everyone.
你不懂，他們殺了所有人
Everyone but me and my baby.
除了我和孩子之外的所有人
They're out there. I saw them on my way here.
他們來了，我在來這的路上看見他們了
They may have seen me. They may have followed me. Please.
他們可能發現我了，他們可能在跟蹤我，求你了
I'm sorry, I can't.
抱歉，我不能開門
If they find us out here, you don't know...
要是他們發現我們在這，你不知道…
Pyp! Open the gate.
派普爾！開門
- I can't. - Sam, is that you?
- 我不能開
- 山姆，是你嗎？
Yes.
是我
Thorne gave me strict orders to not open the gate.
上頭嚴令我不許開門
Oh, Pyp, open the fucking gate!
派普爾，你他媽快給我開門！
I never heard you curse before.
我從來沒聽你罵過人
Yes, well, best get used to it.
那你最好快適應
Are you all right?
你沒事吧？
Shh, you're all right.
噓，你沒事了
Of course you are, my brave little fella.
你肯定會沒事的，勇敢的小傢伙
- It was horrible. - I'm so, so sorry.
- 太可怕了
- 我非常非常抱歉
I didn't know until I got back.
直到回來我才知道
Don't let them send me away, Sam.
不要讓他們趕我走，山姆
- Never. - I know there's no women allowed.
- 絕不會
- 我知道這裏不許有女人
Anyone who tries to throw you out will be having words with me.
誰要趕你走得先過我這關
From now on, wherever you go,
從現在起，不管你去哪
I go, too.
我都跟你一起
Get ready!
備戰！
- Man the gate! - Ready yourselves!
- 守住大門！
- 準備應戰！
Make haste!
快！
- Prepare! - Up on the Wall!
- 快準備！
- 上長城！
Quickly! Up! Up!
趕快！
快上去！上去！
How many? How many are there?
多少？有多少敵人？
Beyond the trees!
在樹那邊！
It's time.
是時候了
Light them up! Light them all!
點著！全點著！
Move!
快走！
Pick up the pace!
快跟上！
Come on, come on.
快點，快點
Here we go, boys, there's one.
準備好，一個
Let's go. There's two.
起！兩個
Let's get the next load.
去拿下一發炮彈
That's the last of the oil, Ser Alliser.
那些是最後的油了，艾裏沙爵士
100,000 you say?
你說有十萬人？
Yes, Ser.
是，爵士
You can say it if you like.
隨便你說吧
We should have sealed the tunnel while we had the chance,
我們應該把隧道封上
like you suggested.
聽你的提議
It was a difficult decision either way, Ser.
本來就是兩難的選擇，爵士
Do you know what leadership means, Lord Snow?
你知道當領導意味著什麼嗎，雪諾大人？
It means that the person in charge gets second-guessed
意味著每個長了嘴的混蛋
by every clever little twat with a mouth.
都可以在事後質疑你
But if he starts second-guessing himself,
但如果領導本人也在事後質疑自己
that's the end--
那就完了
for him, for the clever little twats,
他自己，長嘴的混蛋
for everyone.
所有人，都完了
This is not the end. Not for us.
現在還沒完，我們還沒完
Not if you lot do your duty
只要你們堅守崗位
for however long it takes to beat them back.
直到把敵人擊退
And then you get to go on hating me
然後你才能接著恨我
and I get to go on wishing
我也能接著希望
your wildling whore had finished the job.
你的野人婊子當初下手再准點
You'll be safe down here.
這裏很安全
I'll check on you as soon as I can.
只要有機會我就來看你
You're leaving me again?
你又要離開我？
I'm not leaving you.
我沒要離開你
You're going up there and we're staying down here. That's leaving.
你要上去，而我們留在這下面，這就叫離開
You said from now on we'd stay together.
你說過從現在起我們要在一起
I didn't mean in the same room.
我又不是指在同一房間
What are you going to do out there?
你出去要幹什麼？
- Help my brothers. - How?
- 幫我的兄弟
- 怎麼幫？
You're going to fight the free folk when they come?
自由民來的時候去跟他們打嗎？
They'll kill you. In Mole's Town, they killed everyone.
他們會殺了你，他們殺了鼴鼠村所有的人
I can't just hide here with you while they're fighting out there.
他們正在外面作戰，我不能跟你躲在這裏
Why not? You won't matter up there.
為什麼？你出去也沒什麼用
You will down here.
你在這裏有用
I am a man of the Night's Watch, Gilly.
我是守夜人的一員，吉莉
I made a promise to defend the Wall
我發誓會守衛長城
and I have to keep it
我必須遵守誓言
because that's what men do.
這才是男人
Promise me you won't die.
向我保證你不會死
I promise you I won't die.
我向你保證，我不會死
There's a lot more wildlings on the other side of the Wall than this side.
長城那邊野人比這邊還多
We've got loads of weapons and things.
我們還有這麼多武器之類的
It's the perfect place for us to be.
這裏最適合我們了
I've never thrown a spear before.
我從沒擲過長矛
I've never held a sword with a proper edge.
我從沒拿過開好刃的劍
This is no place for me to be.
這裏一點也不適合我
You're not afraid?
你不害怕？
Of course I'm afraid.
當然害怕
There's a band of wildlings coming to kill us.
一群野人要來殺我們
If you're afraid of a band of wildlings,
如果一群野人你就怕了
how in seven hells did you manage to kill a white walker?
那你怎麼能殺異鬼？
I didn't know I was going to kill it.
我不知道我能殺了它
But I had to do something. I didn't have any choice.
但我必須反擊，別無選擇
It was going to kill Gilly and take the baby.
它要殺死吉莉搶走孩子
If someone had asked me my name right then,
如果當時有人問我叫什麼
I wouldn't have known.
我肯定答不出來
I wasn't Samwell Tarly anymore.
我不再是山姆威爾·塔利
I wasn't a steward in the Night's Watch
不再是守夜人的事務官
or son of Randyll Tarly or any of that.
也不再是藍道·塔利的兒子
I was nothing at all.
我一無所有
And when you're nothing at all,
當你一無所有
there's no more reason to be afraid.
就沒有理由害怕了
But you're afraid now?
但你現在害怕吧？
Yes, well...
是啊…
I'm not nothing anymore.
我不再一無所有
Most of their men are up top.
他們的人大多在上面
Didn't count more than 20 down here.
下面不超過20人
Leftovers.
剩下的
They got a big fat one and a little bony one manning the front.
前面有一個胖子和一個瘦子守著
How high are the walls?
城牆有多高？
Well, we'll be up and over before they know what's happened.
在他們發覺前就能上去
Let's kill some crows!
我們去殺烏鴉吧！
Come on!
上！
Come on, brothers!
上，兄弟們！
Archers nock.
弓箭手上箭
Everyone else hold.
其他人待命
Grenn, no!
葛蘭，別！
I said nock and hold, you cunts!
我說上箭待命，蠢貨！
- Does nock mean draw? - No, Ser!
- 上箭是拉弦的意思嗎？
- 不是，爵士！
- Does fucking hold mean fucking drop? - No, Ser!
- 待命是鬆手的意思嗎？
- 不是，爵士！
- You all plan to die here tonight? - No, Ser!
- 今晚你們想在這裏送命？
- 不想，爵士！
That's very good to hear. Draw!
很好，拉弦
No, down below!
不，下面！
Draw! Light them up.
拉弦，燒死他們
Come on, get up!
快點，起來！
They're attacking the southern gate!
他們在攻南門！
- Now? - Now.
- 現在?
- 是
I'm going down there. Brother Slynt, you have the Wall.
我要下去，史林特兄弟，你守著長城
What?
什麼？
What are you fucking waiting for? Loose!
你他媽還在等什麼，放箭！
You heard the man. Loose!
聽到了吧，放箭！
You, over there.
你，那邊
- Did you get one? - No.
- 你有射中嗎？
- 沒有
Ah, shit, Pyp! Shit.
該死，派普！該死
- Sam. - Yeah?
- 山姆
- 啊？
I think we're gonna die.
我覺得我們死定了
If you keep missing, we will.
你再射不中就真死定了
Come on! Come on!
快！快！
Brothers!
兄弟們！
100 generations have defended this castle.
上百代人守衛了這個城堡
She's never fallen before.
她從未陷落
She will not fall tonight.
今晚也不會
Those are Thenns at our walls.
爬我們城牆的是瑟恩人
They eat the flesh of the men they kill.
他們吃所殺之人的肉
Do you want to fill the belly of a Thenn tonight?
今晚你們想填飽瑟恩人的肚子嗎？
No!
不想！
Tonight we fight.
今晚我們要戰鬥
And when the sun rises, I promise you,
等到天亮，我保證
Castle Black will stand!
黑城堡會屹立不倒！
The Night's Watch will stand.
守夜人會屹立不倒
With me now! Now with me!
跟我上！跟我上！
No discipline. No training.
沒有紀律，未經訓練
Gang of thieves, that's all this is.
只是一幫小偷
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing.
我指揮過君臨都城守備隊
Those men obeyed orders.
他們服從命令
We can't just let them attack the gate!
我們不能任由他們攻門！
The bars of those gates are four inches of cold-rolled steel.
那些城門的門閂是四英吋的冰冷鋼條
Those are giants riding mammoths down there!
他們是騎著猛犸的巨人！
Do you think your cold-rolled steel is gonna stop them?
你覺得你的冰冷鋼條能阻止他們？
No such thing as giants.
哪有巨人
A story for the children.
童話而已
Brother Slynt.
史林特兄弟
We just got word that Ser Alliser needs you below.
我們收到話說艾裏沙爵士在下面需要你
You're the most experienced man he's got, Ser, and he needs you.
你是他身邊經驗最豐富的人，爵士，他需要你
Needed below?
下面需要我？
Yes. Yes.
是，是
Archers, nock your arrows!
弓箭手，上箭！
Nock arrows!
上箭！
Draw!
拉弦！
Loose!
放箭！
They won't summit before dawn.
他們天亮前到不了
How do you know that?
你怎麼知道？
Because I've made that climb.
因為我爬過
I think they're in a bigger hurry than you were.
我覺得他們比你快多了
Hold the bridge!
拉住橋！
Hold, wait for it!
拉住，等等！
Come on with the rocks!
石頭快點！
Nock!
上箭！
Draw!
拉弦！
Loose!
放箭！
Down!
蹲下！
No! No!
不！不！
To the gate. Come on, let's move.
去門那裏，快點，我們走
It's gonna open.
它會開的
I got one right through the heart. He's dead.
我射中一個人的心臟，他死了
- Oh, is it over? - No.
- 結束了？
- 沒有
Well, then...
那麼…
You're all right. You're all right.
你會沒事的
I'll get help.
我去找人幫忙
Shh. Shh.
噓，噓
Maester Aemon is coming.
伊蒙學士來了
He's gonna make it all right.
他會救你的
Shh. Shh.
噓，噓
- Now. - Now!
- 放
- 放！
The outer gate won't hold.
外門抵不住了
Take five men, hold the inner gate.
帶五個人，守住內門
Aye.
是
Hold the gate.
守住門
If they make it through...
一旦他們突破…
They won't.
他們休想
Come on, Hill. And you, Cooper.
過來，希山，還有你，庫珀
You three, on me.
你們三個，跟我來
Come on, you lazy bastards.
快點，懶豬
Oil.
倒油
Oil on the ramp!
油上坡道！
Protect the gate!
守住門！
Get him inside.
帶他進去
Hold the fucking gate!
他媽的守住門！
Hold it!
守住！
We need more men down here.
這裏需要更多人手
- We have to hold the gate. - But we need men here.
- 我們必須守住門
- 但這裏需要人手
Tell Jon. He's in command.
跟瓊恩說，他在指揮
Let's go.
我們走
Get me to the top! You hear me?!
帶我上去！聽到沒？！
Your name's Olly, right?
你是奧利吧？
Listen to me, Olly. Get me to the top.
聽我說，奧利，讓我上去
And when we give the signal, bring us back down.
等我們給信號，再放我們下來
You hear me?
聽到沒？
Find a weapon, Olly. Fight them.
找件武器，奧利，跟他們打
Clear the way! Let's go!
快讓開！我們走！
- Out of the way! - Get out of here!
- 快讓開！
- 離開那裏！
Cut the rope!
砍斷繩子！
Wait! No!
等等！不！
- We need more archers. - Here I am.
- 我們需要弓箭手
- 我來了
- Come on. - Quickly.
- 快點
What are you doing up here?
你來這裏幹嘛？
The wildlings are over the walls.
野人已經翻過城牆
Ser Alliser's fallen.
艾裏沙爵士已倒下了
The castle won't stand much longer.
城堡堅持不了多久
Edd, you have the Wall.
艾迪，長城交給你
If they try the mammoths again, drop fire on them.
如果他們再用猛犸，就投火
If the climbers get too high, drop the scythe on them.
攀爬的人爬高了，就放大鐮刀
Come, brothers. Now fight with me!
來吧，弟兄們，跟我一起！
Might as well enjoy our last night, right, boys?
最後一晚乾脆好好享受，孩子們？
Light the fuckers up!
燒死這幫混蛋！
Nock! Draw!
點火！拉弓！
Loose!
放箭！
How are we gonna stop that?
我們怎麼阻止他？
Shot 20 arrows in him already.
射他20箭
You heard Jon. We hold the gate.
瓊恩說了，守住大門
Jon Snow's not Lord Commander.
瓊恩·雪諾不是指揮官
We hold the gate!
守住大門！
Mother, save me. Father, save me.
聖母，拯救我
天父，拯救我
The gods aren't down here.
神不在這裏
It's the six of us. You hear me?
只有我們6個，你聽到沒？
Night gathers and now my watch begins.
長夜將至，我從今開始守望…
It shall not end until my death.
至死方休
I shall take no wife, hold no lands,
我將不娶妻，不封地…
father no children.
不生子
I shall wear no crown and win no glory.
我將不戴寶冠，不爭榮寵
I shall live and die at my post.
我將盡忠職守，生死於斯
I am the sword in the darkness.
我是黑暗中的利劍
I am the watcher on the walls.
長城上的守衛
I am the shield that guards the realms of men.
守護王國的堅盾
I pledge my life and honor to the Night's Watch
我將生命與榮耀獻給守夜人…
for this night and all the nights to come!
今夜如此，夜夜皆然！
I don't want you out there.
我不希望你出去
You can't protect me forever.
你不能永遠保護我
There won't be anywhere to hide if the castle falls.
城堡陷落，也無處躲藏了
I need him more than I need you.
我需要他多過需要你
We need you, boy.
我們需要你，小子
Ha!
Jon Snow.
瓊恩·雪諾
Hush. Don't talk.
噓，別說話
Do you remember the cave?
還記得山洞嗎？
We should have stayed in the cave.
我們應該待在洞裏
We'll go back there.
我們會回去的
You know nothing, Jon Snow.
你什麼都不知道，瓊恩·雪諾
Drop the scythe, boys!
放鐮刀，兄弟們！
- Hoist her up. - Hoist her up!
- 拖上來
- 拖上來！
They've had enough for one night.
今晚夠他們受的了
Don't cheer too loud.
別高興太早了
They still outnumber us 1,000 to one.
他們仍然千倍於我們
Tormund.
托蒙德
It's over.
結束了
Let it end.
放棄吧
This is how a man ends.
男人應該這樣結束
Put him in chains.
把他鎖起來
We'll question him later.
以後再審問他
from the top of the Wall, boy!
I should have thrown you
我該把你從城牆上推下去的，小子！
Aye.
是啊
You should have.
應該推
Whoa, it's me. It's me.
是我，是我
I promised you, didn't I?
我答應你的，對嗎？
We held them off.
我們頂住了
For one night.
只一晚
This is a great victory.
這是場大勝
A great victory?
大勝？
Mance was testing our defenses.
曼斯只是在測試我們的防守
He almost made it through.
他差點就攻了進來
And he has more giants. He has more mammoths.
他還有很多巨人，很多猛犸
He has 1,000 times as many men.
還有千倍於此的人
They'll hit us again tonight.
他們今晚會再進攻
Maybe we can hold them off for a day or two,
也許我們能頂住一兩天
but we'll never beat them.
但不可能打敗他們
Where are we going?
我們要去哪？
Going to find Mance.
去找曼斯
To fi--- you can't do that.
去找…你不能去
No one gave you any orders.
沒人給你命令
Who's left to give orders?
還有人下命令嗎？
The wildling army's only an army because of Mance.
野人因曼斯而成為軍隊
He united 100 warring tribes.
他聯合了100個殺伐的部落
Without Mance, they lose their leader.
沒有曼斯，就一盤散沙
They lose their purpose. They go back to fighting each other.
沒有目標，他們又會互相爭鬥
Scatter back to their homes.
卸甲歸田
Without Mance?
沒有曼斯？
You're going to kill him?
你要去殺了他？
I'm gonna try.
我要試試
They'll never let you within 100 yards of him.
他們不會讓你靠近他
And even if they did, even if you managed to kill him--
就算靠近了，就算你殺了他…
They'll kill me? If I don't go, they'll kill me anyway.
他們會殺了我？我不去，左右是死
They'll kill the rest of us, too.
他們會殺光我們
They won't just kill you.
他們不會殺你
They'll boil you. They'll flay you.
他們會煮了你，剝皮
They'll make it last days.
折磨你好久
You're right. It's a bad plan.
你說得對，這是下策
What's your plan?
你有辦法嗎？
They held the gate.
他們守住了大門
Get some brothers down here to help you.
找些兄弟下來幫你
We need to burn the bodies.
得把屍體燒了
Raise the outer gate.
升起外門
Then lower it again as soon as I'm out.
我一出去就落閘
What are you doing?
你幹什麼？
I promised Mormont I'd never lose it again.
我答應過莫爾蒙不再弄丟了
In case I don't come back.
以防萬一我回不來
Jon.
瓊恩
Come back.
一定回來
-=TLF字幕组=-
谢谢观赏
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://weibo.com/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/